Register of the Voldemars Salnais papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Voldemars Salnais papers
1901-1973
75069
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes, 1 album box (3.2 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, clippings, printed matter, and photographs relating to Latvian independence movements, foreign relations, and women's organizations; Latvians in Siberia (Vladivostok); and the Office of the Latvian Representative in the Far East and Siberia. Includes some materials collected by Milda Salnais.
Salnais, Voldemars, 1886-1948.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1975.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1886 Born
1920 Vice Director, Latvian Central Bureau of Statistics
1921 Delegate to the League of Nations, Vice Minister of Foreign Affairs
1923 Delegate to the League of Nations
1925 Minister of Public Welfare
1926 Delegate to the International Labor Organization
1927 Director, Central Bureau of Statistics
1933 Delegate to the League of Nations
1934 Director, Central Bureau of Statistics
1937-1940 Minister to Sweden, Norway and Denmark
1940-1945 Organizer of National Underground in Baltic States
1948 Died
Latvia--Foreign relations--Scandinavia.; Latvia--Foreign relations.; Latvia--History--1918-1940.; Latvia--History--Soviet occupation, 1940-1941.; Latvia.; Latvians--Siberia (Russia); Nationalism--Latvia.; Scandinavia--Foreign relations--Latvia.; Scandinavia.; Siberia (Russia); Soviet Union.; Women--Latvia.; World War, 1939-1945--Latvia.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Diaries, 1935-1948
  Scope and Contents note
  Diaries, handwritten by Voldemars Salnais.
  - Diary, 1934-1938 (Box-folder : 1: 1)
  - Diary, 1939-1943 (Box-folder : 1: 2)
  - Diary, 1943-1948 (Box-folder : 1: 3)
- Subject File, 1918-1945
  Comprised of correspondence, memoranda, reports, lists, notes, clippings, and printed matter.
  - Baltic independence, 1944 (Box-folder : 1: 4)
  - Latvian Central Council, circa 1940 (Box-folder : 1: 5)
  - Latvian National Council and Office of Representative in the Siberia, 1918-1919 (Box-folder : 1: 6)
  - Latvian women, organizations, etc., circa 1920-1930 (Box-folder : 1: 7)
  - Latvian Young Men's Christian Association (Y.M.C.A.) in Siberia, 1919 (Box-folder : 1: 8)
  - National League of Women in Latvia, circa 1925 (Box-folder : 1: 10)
- Miscellany, 1886-1973
  Miscellaneous notes, clippings, and printed matter.
  - Miscellany, 1886-1924 (Box-folder : 2: 1)
  - Miscellany, circa 1906-1970 (Box-folder : 2: 2)
  - Miscellany, circa 1920-1940 (Box-folder : 2: 3)
  - Miscellany, circa 1921-1937 (Box-folder : 2: 4)
  - Miscellany, circa 1922-1948 (Box-folder : 2: 5)
  - Miscellany, circa 1924-1964 (Box-folder : 2: 6)
  - Miscellany, circa 1928-1942 (Box-folder : 2: 7)
  - Miscellany, circa 1937 (Box-folder : 2: 8)
  - Miscellany, 1937-1938 (Box-folder : 2: 9)
  - Miscellany, circa 1937-1947 (Box-folder : 2: 10)
  - Miscellany, circa 1940-1960 (Box-folder : 2: 11)
  - Miscellany, circa 1940-1961 (Box-folder : 2: 12)
  - Miscellany, 1970-1973 (Box-folder : 3: 1)
  - Miscellany, Undated (Box-folder : 3: 2-3)